morningside.edu 2019-03-28

# Privacy Statement | Morningside College

## We respect your privacy

Morningside College respects the privacy of all visitors to our website and our affiliated sites. Our policy is to protect your privacy.

The following is intended to give insight into what information we collect, how the information is used, and other information for protecting your privacy. This information applies to use of morningside.edu, as well as Morningside’s official affiliated sites.

_**As of May 2018, this policy language is in review and pending official adoption by Morningside.**_

###   
Use of Morningside Content

You may use Morningside’s content for your own purposes provided the following criteria are met:

  * The website's content is used for informational and noncommercial purposes only; 
  * No text, graphics, or other content available from this website are modified in any way; and
  * No website graphics are used, copied, or distributed separate from accompanying text.

The Morningside logo may not be used in any electronic or printed publications without permission from Morningside. Please contact [edlunde@morningside.edu](mailto:edlunde@morningside.edu?subject=Logo%20Inquiry) for additional details.

### Personal Information Collection

Personal information from you collected by Morningside College is treated as confidential and is used only to fulfill your request or provide a service to you. We collect this information in a variety of ways, including online applications, various contact and registration forms, and e-mail. Please note that this policy is for Morningside’s website and affiliated sites only and does not apply to other third party web sites linked to from our web site. Please check the privacy policies on those web sites for more information.

### Information Automatically Collected

Morningside uses data to better personalize your website experience. The college automatically collects certain pieces of information, including your IP address, your Internet service provider, your time on the website, and navigation path on the website. We use this information to provide you with the best possible information service. We also use cookies - small collections of data saved in your temporary internet folders - to keep statistics on user sessions and server hits. Web server activity is logged on a temporary basis and then deleted from our system. Google Analytics are also used to collect user data, including demographic and geographic information.

The search engine on morningside.edu and affiliated sites tracks words that are searched, when these words are searched, how often they are searched, and other such data. We keep this information confidential and use it to improve the efficiency of our search engine, to gauge what information is important to our users, and to guide the development and maintenance of the website.

### Third Parties

Morningside College sometimes uses remarketing and other online advertising and research to better reach our students and parents. The college uses third-party vendors, including Google, to show ads on sites across the Internet. To opt out of Google's use of cookies, please visit Google's Ads Settings. Also, if you would like to opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.

Morningside College does not distribute personal information to third-party vendors. Your information is for internal use only. Morningside College may share some of the information collected with contracted third-party vendors, companies who are acting on our behalf, or jointly with Morningside under a contractual arrangement when necessary to fulfill services. We may also share information when required to do so by law.

Whenever possible, we do not share information with third-party vendors unless they have agreed in writing to provide the same level of privacy protection as provided by Morningside.

We do not disclose private information about you for the purposes of marketing or soliciting products or services other than our own.

The Morningside College site and affiliated sites contains links to web sites operated by parties not affiliated with Morningside College. We link to these sites in order to facilitate access to information that may be useful to you. Morningside College cannot control and is not responsible for the content contained on the web sites of non-affiliated parties. Morningside College is not responsible for the privacy policies of non-affiliated parties. We encourage you to review the security practices of these sites. A reference or link to any specific products, process, publication, or service does not necessarily constitute or imply an endorsement by Morningside College, nor do views represent the views of Morningside College or its employees and students.

### E-Commerce

Some of our website features may use applications to collect data to facilitate an e-commerce transaction. In this case we use third-party vendors with an approved banking relationship to process credit card transactions. All credit card information is encrypted and only the information needed to complete a transaction history is stored on secure servers.

###   
Use of Personal Information by Morningside

Morningside College may use your personal information to contact you via email or by postal mail with newsletters, marketing, or promotional materials. The input of that information is voluntary, and opt-out options will be available should you wish to discontinue communication at any time. To update your records, please contact the Morningside Alumni Office.  

### Security

Our site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control.

###   
Affiliated Websites and Links

The Morningside website may contain destination links to other websites including Morningside student groups, third-party organizations outside of the morningside.edu domain, and more.

Morningside College is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such websites. These destination links are provided only for your convenience, and as such, you access them at your own risk. Any information you reveal on any such site is not subject to this privacy statement. You should consult the privacy policies of each site you visit; however, we wish to ensure the integrity of our website and its destination links, so any comments pertaining to any sites accessed through destination links on our website are greatly appreciated. Please contact us.  

### Privacy Statement Changes

Morningside College may update or change the privacy statement. Revisions will be reflected on the website. Your use of the website constitutes acceptance of the most current privacy statement. If you do not agree to the terms of the privacy statement, then please exit and discontinue use of the website immediately.  

### Surveys

From time to time, this website requests that website users participate in the sharing of information via survey. Filling out the survey is completely voluntary. Some of the information requested may include contact information and other relevant information.  

### Questions

Please direct questions about this privacy statement to: [edlunde@morningside.edu](mailto:edlunde@morningside.edu?subject=Website%20Policy)
